One memorable data wrangling experience for
我有一次难忘的数据整理经历
me was for an article that I was writing for my hockey blog.
我给曲棍球博客写了一篇文章
I'm quite a bad hockey player but a huge analytics geek and Toronto Maple Leafs fan.
我的曲棍球玩得很烂 但我是一个分析极客和多伦多枫叶队超级粉丝
So the Leafs were really,
枫叶队在很长时间内
really bad for a really long time.
表现得很差劲
Like last in the league bad last year.
有多烂呢？去年联盟垫底
Then at the start of the season all of a sudden they were scoring goals like crazy.
但从本赛季开始 他们突然疯狂得分
I was curious. Could this be the most improved team ever?
我很好奇 枫叶队是历史上进步最大的球队吗？
The data I needed to answer that question was spread across three different data sets,
我需要用数据来回答 它们主要分布在三个不同的数据集中
because the person that compiled the data didn't organize it very well.
因为编制数据的人员没有安排好
You'll see what I mean in a second.
你马上就会明白我为何这样说
That made data wrangling for this project pretty complicated.
因为那样的编排导致本项目的数据整理变得尤为复杂
So the process started with downloading those three files.
所以 我的工作从下载三个数据文件开始
One here, a second here,
第一个 第二个
and a third here.
第三个也下载好了
Each file contained data about how well or
每个文件都包含了
poorly each team was able to score or prevent goals.
每队得分或被得分的表现
Most of these column headings will probably look like gibberish to you and that's okay,
大部分列标题看上去毫无意义 但没关系
I'll explain the ones you need to know for this to make sense along the way.
对此 我会在此阐述你需知的部分
After importing the data then I started assessing it.
导入数据后 我开始评估
And these datasets they were wildly different.
这些数据集有很大不同
There's one here, a second here, and a third here.
第一个在这里 这是第二个 这是第三个
The first one and the third one,
第一个数据集和第三个数据集的数据
had their data broken down by season.
按赛季 (season) 划分
While this one in the middle had it broken down by game.
中间的数据由比赛场次 (game) 划分
I was going to have to standardize these before I could do any analysis.
开始分析之前 我准备对这些数据做标准化处理
Then, I noticed that these two datasets,
然后 我注意到了这两个数据集
the second and third one had the data broken down as total goals,
第二个和第三个数据集含有单次总得分
while this first one had it broken down as a rate stat.
第一个数据集含有进球率统计数据
Goals per hour of game time is a rate stat,
即比赛中每小时进球数
just like miles or kilometers per hour is
正如每小时英里数/公里数
or even click through rate in online advertising,
在线营销点击率或
like clicks per views.
每次访问点击次数
Team is played slightly different amounts of
赛队的比赛时间有些许不同
time so comparing totals to judge goal scoring skill is unfair.
根据总分判断进球能力不太公平
Totals vs rates is something you'll encounter a bunch in your data wrangling career.
总分 VS 进球率在数据整理过程中较为常见
So to get the rate stat that I wanted, goals per hour,
得出我想要的进球率统计数据 (进球数/小时)
I would need to divide by the total number of
要用每支球队总进球数除以
goals for each team by the number of minutes they played,
比赛总时长
also known as time on ice.
上场分钟数也被称为冰上时间
TOI stands for time on ice,
简称是 TOI
which these two datasets had.
这两个数据集都有 TOI 数据
One-two, but this one didn't.
表一表二中有 但这个表上没有记录
What? At this point I paused.
什么？ 此时我停了下来
When I first started data wrangling noticing
当我初次开始整理数据时
a few issues in a row like this would stress me out.
连续发现诸如此类的一些问题 让我感到压力巨大
There was so much work to do and now it just felt forever away.
我有太多的事要做 感觉永远都做不完
What I learned was that if you write down each issue,
我所知的方法是 如果把每个问题都写下来
pause and take a moment to digest what you need to do,
停一会儿 揣摩你要做的事
wrangling becomes enjoyable, like a detective at work methodically solving a mystery.
整理工作就变得让人感到快乐 像是一个执行任务的侦探在有条不紊地解开谜题
So I paused, wrote the issues down, took a deep breath.
所以 我停下来写下问题 深呼吸
I had to fill in this missing time on ice data in this third data set somehow.
然而 我必须填写出第三个数据集的冰上时间数据
There wasn't a file easily available for download,
没有可以轻易下载的参考资料
so I had to scrape it off a different hockey stats website.
我必须从不同曲棍球统计网站上把数据采集下来
It was this time on ice column here,
这就是 TOI 列
TOI again stands for time on ice.
TOI 代表冰上时间
This site had the data for several seasons and broken down by each team.
该网站记录了几个赛季的数据 并按各支队伍划分
Scraping is just a fancy way of saying
采集数据只是
extracting data from websites using code, by the way.
用代码从网站上提取数据的一种漂亮说法
I won't show you how I did it here,
但在这里我不会展示如何操作
but it's a really handy skill and pretty magical
但它是很方便的技巧且相当神奇
actually and we'll cover it in more detail on the second lesson in this course.
其实我们会在本课第二节中更详细地讲述
So, now we have the missing time on ice data with the results from the scraping here.
现在我们从采集来的数据中得到了缺少的 TOI 数据
But one thing with scraping is that the results come in string form.
但采集的数据以字符串形式存在
I needed integers to form multiplication and division to
而我需要整数进行乘除
create that rate stat that we'd talked about previously,
以创建前面讨论过的进球率统计数据
goals per 60 minutes.
即每小时进球数
So conversion from string to integer was going to be necessary.
所以 将字符串转换成整数很有必要
Not a problem, we can do that.
这并不难 我们能做到
Then, I noticed there were more problems with that scraped data.
然而 我注意到采集的数据有更多问题
The previous three datasets that we downloaded here: one, two,
我们下载的前三个数据集
three had team names in their abbreviation form.
都包含了每个赛队的缩写名称
BOS stands for Boston, PIT stands for Pittsburgh,
例如 BOS 代表波斯顿队、PIT 代表匹兹堡队、
TOR stands for Toronto for example,
TOR 代表多伦多队
but the scraped data had the full team name.
但是采集的数据包含的是完整队名
There's Boston, there's Pittsburgh, there's Toronto.
即波斯顿 (Boston)、匹兹堡 (Pittsburgh) 和多伦多 (Toronto)
These needed to be standardized or merging each teams missing time on ice data,
需要将这些名称进行标准化 或在 TOI 数据中合并缺失的每队冰上时间数据
among other things wouldn't work.
另外还有一些问题
There is more stuff that I needed to clean to answer
要回答这个问题 需要清理的数据还有很多
this question that I won't discuss right now, but you get the point.
我现在不会马上讨论 但你要明白这一点
Data is dirty especially when it comes from different sources.
当数据来源较多时 容易形成脏数据
Assessing the data here was necessary to identify and fix all of these issues.
要找到和修复所有这些问题 有必要评估这里的数据
Once that was done, I wrote all of the required cleaning code to fix these issues,
评估一完成 我会写出一切所需的清理代码 以解决这些问题
then performed one calculation which is the analysis part and that was it.
然后 执行一次计算 完成分析部分
All that was left was creating the visualizations and actually writing the article.
剩下的工作是创建可视化内容并写成文章
Was all that work worth it?
前面那些工作值得吗？
It's fun to play data detective,
扮演数据侦探的角色很有趣
so that's a definite yes for me.
答案是肯定的
Also my hunch was true,
我的预感是对的
the Leafs were the most improved team ever at that point in the season,
就得分能力而言
in terms of their goal scoring ability.
枫叶队是截止当时进步最快的球队
I literally jumped out of my seat when I sorted the table and saw them at the top,
当完成表格分类 看到枫叶队排名榜首 我直接从座位上跳了起来
which is way more clear via the slope in this slope graph or the bars in this bar chart.
坡度图和柱状图表现得更清晰